<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: Core -->
  <Core.label>Inti (core)</Core.label>
  <!-- EN: Core RimWorld content. -->
  <Core.description>Konten inti (core) di RimWorld.</Core.description>

  <!-- EN: Ideology -->
  <Ideology.label>Ideologi (Ideology)</Ideology.label>
  <!-- EN: Create your own belief system with fine control over behaviors, preferences, rituals, symbols, and more. Play as pirate nudist cannibals, blind undergrounder mole people, charitable ranching cowboys, machine-obsessed transhumanists, and more.\n\nAssign social roles like leader, moral guide, and specialist to your colonists.\n\nHold unforgettable rituals: Dance parties, cannibal feasts, burn and smoke circles, skylantern festivals, sacrifices, gladiator duels, blindings, scarifications, funerals, and more.\n\nConnect with Gauranlen trees and command the dryads that live inside them.\n\nHunt for ancient relics. Explore long-forgotten ruins, hack downed spacedrones, and infiltrate tribal villages. Attract wealthy pilgrims by presenting your relics in reliquaries. Plunder ancient complexes for treasure. Raid temporary encampments. Help beggars in need, or betray them.\n\nEnslave prisoners to perform work or fight for you.\n\nPlace many new buildings linked to belief systems, and see the many visual styles of different beliefs.\n\nUse new apparel, tattoos, and hairstyles desired by believers.\n\nSeek transcendence through a machine god in the new archonexus endgame. -->
  <Ideology.description>Buat sistem kepercayaan sendiri dengan kontrol yang baik atas perilaku, preferensi, ritual, simbol, dan banyak lagi. Bermain sebagai bajak laut kanibal yang telanjang, orang bawah tanah yang buta, koboi peternakan, transhumanis yang terobsesi dengan mesin, dan banyak lagi.\n\nTetapkan peran sosial seperti: pemimpin, pemandu moral, dan spesialis untuk koloni anda.\n\nSelenggarakan ritual yang tak terlupakan: Pesta dansa, pesta kanibal, lingkaran bakar dan asap, festival lentera, pengorbanan, duel gladiator, pembutaan, skarifikasi, pemakaman, dan banyak lagi.\n\nTerhubung dengan pohon Gauranlen dan perintahkan dryad yang hidup di dalamnya.\n\nBerburu relik kuno. Jelajahi reruntuhan yang terlupakan, bajak pesawat luar angkasa yang jatuh, dan infiltrasi desa. Pikat peziarah kaya dengan menghadirkan relik anda. Menjarah kompleks kuno untuk harta karun. Menyerang kamp sementara. Bantu pengemis yang membutuhkan, atau khianati mereka.\n\nTahanan budak untuk melakukan pekerjaan atau berjuang untukmu.\n\nTempatkan banyak bangunan baru yang terkait dengan sistem kepercayaan, dan lihat gaya visual dari kepercayaan berbeda.\n\nGunakan pakaian baru, tato, dan gaya rambut yang diinginkan oleh orang.\n\nCari transendensi melalui dewa mesin di akhir game archonexus yang baru.</Ideology.description>
  
  <!-- EN: Royalty -->
  <Royalty.label>Kerajaan (Royalty)</Royalty.label>
  <!-- EN:Fight or ally with the new Shattered Empire faction.\n\nGain psychic powers through noble right, tribal nature communion, or artifact theft. Strengthen them through meditation, and use them to win battles and socially influence people. Strengthen your psychic power by meditating in grand thronerooms, in nature, before flames, the dead or blank walls.\n\nComplete quests to earn honor and titles, or riches and gear. Host rich nobles, poor refugees, animals, prisoners, and more. Defend crashed shuttles, serve as aerial shock troops, build monuments, defeat enemies, and recruit visitors.\n\nUse the special privileges of nobility to call Imperial troops, shuttles, and orbital strikes.\n\nNew mechanoid clusters may deploy on your map. Wear them down with artillery, do sneaky sabotage, or lure enemies into the danger.\n\nWield persona weapons with unique traits. Use jump packs for tactical flight and shield packs for emergency defense. Wear cataphract armor, locust armor, grenadier armor, and phoenix armor, each with different tools. Install new body implants to augment brains, stomachs, arms, and skin.\n\nEnjoy a new album of music by Alistair Lindsay.\n\nHost and protect the Stellarch and his guards complete the new royal endgame quest -->
  <Royalty.description>Bertarung atau bersekutu dengan faksi peninggalan kerajaan yang hancur.\n\nDapatkan kekuatan psikis melalui hak mulia, bersekutu dengan suku pedalaman, atau mencuri artefak. Perkuat koloni melalui meditasi, dan gunakan untuk memenangkan pertemputean dan mempengaruhi orang. Perkuat kekuatan meditasi anda dengan meditasi di ruang singgahsana yang megah, di alam, di depan api, di dinding yang kosong.\n\nSelesaikan misi untuk mendapatkan kehormatan dan gelar, atau kekayaan dan perlengkapan. Tuan rumah bangsawan kaya, pengungsi miskin, hewan, tahanan, dan masih banyak lagi. Pertahankan pesawat ulang-alik yang jatuh, yang berfungsi sebagai pasukan kejut udara, bangun monumen, kalahkan musuh, dan rekrut pengunjung.\n\nGunakan hak istimewa kaum bangsawan untuk memanggil pasukan kekaisaran, pesawat ulang-alik, dan serangan orbital.\n\nKluster mekanik baru ditempatkan pada peta anda. Hancurkan mereka dengan altileri, lakuka sabotase licik, atau memancing musuh ke dalam bahaya.\n\nGunakan senjata persona dengan cirinya yang unik. Gunakan paket lompat untuk penerbangan taktis dan paket pelindung untuk pertahanan darurat. Kenakan zirah katafrak, zirah belalang, zirah granat, dan zirah phoenix, yang masing memiliki fungsi yang berbeda. Pasang implan tubuh baru untuk menambah otak, perut, legan, dan kulit.\n\nNikmati album musik baru oleh Alistair Lindsay.\n\nLindungi tuan rumah stellarch dan pengawalnya hingga akhir permainan kerajaan selesai</Royalty.description>
  
</LanguageData>